Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims papers, Inclusive: 1943-1971, undated, Bulk: 1908-2012, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims papers
Inclusive: 1943-1971, undated, Bulk: 1908-2012, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3925
Sims, Nora Elizabeth Potter
2 document boxes.
The Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims Papers contains materials including diaries, notebooks, correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and artifacts all pertaining to Nora's life.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims was born on 1914 November 14 to Samuel Potter and Margaret Ava Orr in Brandon, Texas. She had five siblings all of whom died before her except her sister Mable. After receiving her B.S. degree in Elementary Education from Texas Tech College, she taught at New Deal Consolidated School in New Deal, Texas, until 1943, when she became an instructor at Amarillo Air Base, teaching pilots how to repair electrical systems on B-17s and B-29s. In 1953, she completed her Master of Education degree at West Texas State College in Canyon, Texas. Prior to her retirement in 1971, she was a Jr. High teacher with Phillips Independent School District.
Nora Potter Sims was married to Myrle Andrew Sims on 1949 August 27. They were the first couple to be married in the First Presbyterian Church of Borger. She was a member of the Texas Education Association and National Education Association and Texas Retired Teachers Association. Sims was also a member of #811 Order of the Eastern Star, Home Demonstration Club, and Hutchinson County Retired Teachers Association. Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims passed away on 2012 September 2.
Scope and Content
The Nora Elizabeth Potter Sims papers range in date from 1908-2012. Materials deal exclusively with Nora’s life, with the majority falling between her time as an instructor for the Amarillo Air Base beginning in 1943 and her retirement as a teacher in 1971. There are also documents related to a home she purchased with her husband, personal documents such as birth certificates and an immunization record, and her funeral arrangements.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, this collection did not have an original order. The documents have been arranged topically and the folders organized alphabetically. The material within the folders are in chronological order with the exception of the photographs as most of them are not dated.
Currently, the collection is organized in one series: I. Personal Material.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3925. Acquired 2014-08-20
Index Terms
Subjects
Women -- Texas -- Diaries.; Women -- Texas.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Women.
Genres
Legal documents.; Memorial service programs.; Photographs.
- Personal Material, 1943-1971; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  These papers pertain to Nora Potter Sim's life. The bulk of the materials fall between 1943 and 1971 dealing primarily with her employment as an instructor at the Amarillo Air Base and as a teacher for the Phillips Independent School District. There are also a variety of legal documents, diaries, photographs, and 3-D objects. The collection is in overall good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Flash memory devices; Photographic print
  - Artifacts, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diaries, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diaries, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diaries, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diaries, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Diaries, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federal Employment (1 of 2), 1945 March-1949 July (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Federal Employment (2 of 2), 1945 March-1949 July (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Flash Drive, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Legal Papers-Insurance, 1948 October-1949 October (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Legal Papers-Property Purchase, 1948 July and 1985 September (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Personal Papers (1 of 2), 1941 July-1953 April (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Personal Papers (2 of 2), 1941 July-1953 April (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs (1 of 4), 1908-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs (2 of 4), 1908-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photographs (3 of 4), 1908-1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs (4 of 4), 1908-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Teaching Records (1 of 4), 1949 June-1971 February (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Teaching Records (2 of 4), 1949 June-1971 February (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Teaching Records (3 of 4), 1949 June-1971 February (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Teaching Records (4 of 4), 1949 June-1971 February (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Training Notebook, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Training Notebook, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Obituary and Funeral Program, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - West Texas State College (1 of 2), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - West Texas State College (2 of 2), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)